<Narrative>
    <IntroText> Geographically, the Near East extends from the western coasts
                of Turkey and the Levant to the eastern border of Iran.
                All its different civilizations, which span millennia, are
                culturally and historically referred to as 'Near Eastern'.

                Around 8000 B.C., in many places across the Near East, people
                who had up to then lived as hunter-gatherers began to establish
                fixed settlements and to practise agriculture and stock
                breeding. From about 6200 B.C. on, pottery started to be
                manufactured, and from roughly 5000 B.C. metal objects.
                The population increased, the settlements grew, and in many
                places artificial irrigation became necessary. All this
                ultimately required social organization, and in about 3400 B.C.
                some settlements emerged as city-states.</IntroText>
    <Period>8000 b.c. - 500 b.c.</Period>
    <Objects>
        <Object id="0">
            <Name>Tablet with enveloppe</Name>
            <FileName>APM06430</FileName>
            <Summary>rectangular envelope with cuneiform script and stamp print</Summary>
            <Text>  Cuneiform writing appeared around 3300 B.C. in Mesopotamia and
                    continued in use until the beginning of our era. The name
                    refers to the wedge-shaped markings of the characters
                    (cuneus is Latin for 'wedge'). These were pressed into the
                    clay with a reed stylus which made a triangular imprint;
                    their long, tapering form was made by moving the stylus as
                    if to draw a line. Cuneiform was adopted over the entire
                    Near East to write very dissimilar languages. The script
                    found acceptance for administration and contracts as well
                    as for religious and literary writings. It was deciphered
                    in the nineteenth century thanks to the efforts of Georg
                    Grotefend and Henry Rawlinson.</Text>
            <Links>
                <Link>
                    <ObjectId>1</ObjectId>
                    <ObjectName>Cylinder seal</ObjectName>
                    <LinkType>Marks of this type of seal can be found on the tablet.</LinkType>
                </Link>
            </Links>
        </Object>
        <Object id="1">
            <Name>Cylinder seal</Name>
            <FileName>APM03215</FileName>
            <Summary>   old-Babylonian seal cylinder; left Gilgamesh, right Engidu,
                        in conflict with lion and bull; inscription: Lu-Schak,
                        the writer, son of Bil-Sag</Summary>
            <Text>  From the sixth millennium on, seals were used to 'sign' a
                    statement. About 3400 B.C. in Mesopotamia the stamp seal
                    was replaced with the cylinder seal. It has the shape of a
                    cylindrical bead with an axial hole, and could be worn
                    suspended from a cord. An image was cut into the outer
                    surface, and when it was rolled over a moist clay surface
                    the image appeared in relief in the clay. Cylinder seals
                    were manufactured in all kinds of material ranging from
                    semi-precious stones to glass paste.</Text>
            <Links>
                <Link>
                    <ObjectId>0</ObjectId>
                    <ObjectName>Tablet With Enveloppe</ObjectName>
                    <LinkType>This tablet was found in the same region.</LinkType>
                </Link>
                <Link>
                    <ObjectId>2</ObjectId>
                    <ObjectName>Axe with Pins</ObjectName>
                    <LinkType>This Axe was used by the same subculture.</LinkType>
                </Link>
            </Links>
        </Object>
        <Object id="2">
            <Name>Axe with Pins</Name>
            <FileName>APM12851</FileName>
            <Summary>   axe; blade at stem narrow and straight with 2 ribs,
                        then flared at the bottom to 1/4 circle;</Summary>
            <Text>  In the territory of present Iran, Elam was dominant for most
                    of the fourth millennium. About 2000 B.C. Indo-European
                    tribes lived in northeastern Iran. The extent of their
                    settlements can be traced by the geographical dispersion of
                    their characteristic polished pottery. By roughly 1300 B.C.
                    they reached Amlash (APM09176), whereas in Luristan,
                    renowned for its bronze objects, the earliest polished
                    pottery is found not until the eighth century. </Text>
            <Links>
                <Link>
                    <ObjectId>1</ObjectId>
                    <ObjectName>Cylinder Seal</ObjectName>
                    <LinkType>This Seal was used by the same subculture.</LinkType>
                </Link>
            </Links>
        </Object>
    </Objects>
</Narrative>
